you
hi all good evening
uh
guys am i audible
and visible
thank you somebody
so
let me share my screen
guys again
do let me know if you can see my screen share
screen share
cool
so guys
have you attended
class by
Anshuman
on the weekend
did it help
you guys
right
great
uh
team
I also
I
Okay
.
so I did this let me try to execute this one now once I go and clear execute this
part now if you see still we are able to execute this happens actually one after
the other now these are the these syntaxes that we have seen this
multiple times in last three classes and we have all know this but do you see
this like even if I want to do in series calls this takes actually this syntax if
we can improve this thing better like we are returning this again we are calling
this what we are actually doing it here what is actually happening here when I
mean doing in series what I meant to say is that once this call is successful
only then go to the next call isn't it that is what we are saying it only if
this post call is successful then go to next thing if user call is successful
then go to next thing if comments call is successful then go to next thing if
if any of the API calls fails in between then go to the cache block directly
isn't it now in order to improvise these sort of
syntaxes right where you see the chaining now if you're saying when we
were actually making a multiple parallel calls they improved a lot they went on
to do it magical things in a same way what if we can say that we make an API
call and we say that hey can you wait till this call is returning the data
only once it returns the data you can go to the next API call so that sort of
syntaxes itself right then and those sort of syntaxes itself we come across
something called async await now what async await talks about it let me write
down the logic and say it like firstly when to use this keyword async is that
whenever you write a function which is in async nature okay now what I'm
writing is get all information let's say in this get all information I'm trying
to fetch the right set of data now all the information here let's say this
related to user or post or comment I'm trying to fetch this information now I
say that whatever logic I write inside is all asynchronous in nature then I say
that it's async now inside this I have to write two things firstly let's say I
make a constant I say user it's a user info inside this user info what I'll do
is that I'll say that await okay my fetch data inside it I'll pass on user
URL again I'll try to write the next thing it's I try to fetch the for post
info
again I try to fetch the information called comments URL comment info await
my fetch data comments info okay but what we have to make sure is that we
were earlier discussing something like synchronous that one thing should happen
after the other here that same thing await is doing what await does inside an
async function is that if there is an await added anywhere so there code
executes code get you know this code asynchronous good halted like this get
halted until unless this line is resolved is this clear is I mean this
thing is actually removed from call stack whenever you see an await all
other things get executed simultaneously but only once this data is resolved this
will store in user info then it will go and try to make another API call
okay I hope you are able to understand what await is doing await is actually
still making an API call this is still in serious format but do you see this
thing like I'm okay I'm handling right use cases like if I'm able to fetch the
right information that's fine but how do I handle error cases here anyone having
any idea how can I handle error cases here do you know any exceptional
handling methods how do you do exceptional handling try catch do you
guys agree that I can use a try catch block where I say that hey if all these
things are successful all great but if there is anything which is failing
console log with the error is this clear race that I hope you understood that
what exceptional handling is that if all the like if you see here we had three
then cases I've had it three await calls for them and one error handling
method catch block here so I'm trying not I can say you can say that Maneshwara
that it works for serious use cases mostly because it is actually waiting
for the other call to come I'll talk about how can you make a parallel calls
using await okay give me some time but generally it works for serious calls
okay now let's say if I want to execute this one how would I execute I'll say
that get all information and this sent it now let's say I try to copy this
code and put it here once I paste it here and I call this function now do you
see this it printed me right away all this information this is still working
this is still working in asynchronous fashion but it made my work completely
easy isn't it if I want to make a series calls does my syntax look clean now does
my syntax look clean guys simple right I make I tell that whole this function is
asynchronous in nature I say that whichever call I need to get I'm
actually waiting for that response then I'm moving it to the next API call okay
this is what async await does for us this is an example of serious event but
if I want to make an API call where I'm actually making all the things in
parallel right how can I do it
any idea just now we have discussed how can you trigger all the API cons in
parallel what would you use here guys watch which method will come in this
use case in the methods that we have discussed just now can I say promise
start all inside an array I'll pass this one by one
and let's say once this API calls are successful I try to console log the data
now all this parallel calls are also when I say promised at all it is
actually converted into one call isn't it from the logical perspective though
behind the scenes there are three calls being done this is the same code isn't
it this is the same code isn't it one is actually taking some long amount of time
this the above function will take long amount of time come this is parallel
calls this is serious call guys do you understand this logic how this is
working parallel in nature give me a few more reactions guys is before just want
to know whether you are able to catch up this one this is just a better syntax of
handling promises other than using a then and catch block instead of then we
use something called a wait and we still write that same logical part now let's
see if I try to print this logic again still see if you see right away I've
got the data right so this is how this thing works guys like it's it's pretty
straightforward pretty easy how this asynchronous JS works but all the
asynchronous was mostly the return type is promises and wherever you see that
it is a time-taking event in order to handle you promises you have dot then and
dot catch or else you can use await and and the combination of try and catch
where you say that if there is a successful call this will execute in the
block or else will go into catch block where it will handle the error handling
okay if you want to make a serious calls and this is a pretty much clean code
where you make all three series calls one by one after the other where this
line of code will be only executed when this call is being done successfully if
this thing fails it will directly go into the catch block and stop it because
are you able to follow up or is there is anyone who didn't understand this logic
just want to know this do you understand this use case I did I did I went speed
did I over speed it or it's it's it's simple and straightforward yeah so yeah
let's do this guys what I have just done it if you see here earlier when I'm
trying to make a serious cuts my fetch I was actually trying to make a one call
API call and then I was handling successful use case using dot then now
in order to handle like let's say this dot then one after the other when I'm
writing this sort of logic it's still complicated it still looks like you know
call back inside a call back inside a call back even dot then dot then dot
catch like to improve the syntax of how do you make a series of calls there is
a new way of writing there's a new way that was introduced again called a sync
await now whenever you want to use this of syntax firstly you have to tell
whatever function I'm writing it that is in asynchronous mode all those things
are happening inside even if there is a one await call you have to call that
function as asynchronous once you say that function is asynchronous then
whichever return type is promised let's say this my fetch data data is actually
returning as a promise and then we know that it can take time earlier in order
to handle this promise you are using dot then function but here you can say that
await wait for this result whenever this API call will get resolved wait for till
then point once it is resolved store it in user info and this line of execution
will only happen first until as this is not successful it won't go to the next
steps this all next steps only when this is successful it will go to the next step
this one so we at the at this line we are actually waiting where we are not
processing it we are waiting for this data this is what it is ensuring us they
are making a sequence series call in a sequence okay but if we want to make
this itself is in a parallel call is that what I did is like I used one way
await and I say that hey promise dot org give me all the all the data at one
shot if it is all successful give me it or else throw an error at one shot is
this clear Ganesh this is just a syntactic sugar how can you handle this
promises you other than using dot then and dot catch you can wrap it a try and
catch block much more readable much more clear much more better so in your
projects in your things wherever you go mostly you will be using a sinker with
syntaxes with this sort of syntax where you might make a single API call or if
you want to make a parallel calls you will come with among these three use
cases that we have learned either to use from start all or all settled or race
okay this this this sort of use cases you'll generally see it I hope this you
understand the syntax I'll what I'll do is that I'll give you another example a
dummy example itself let's say a built example I'll just add a new code example
let's say one dot JS okay so I have this code now what I have done it what I
have pasted it here is that let's say there is again a fetch user data which
is creating a producer code where you see a set timeout with something random
value of thousand milliseconds we are returning still user information based
on the user ID whatever pass you pass an user ID one two three or anything will
fetch that information and that if user is valid data is there it will resolve
or it will reject that user is not found okay now the same thing I have built it
for fetch post dummy data okay I'm trying to replicate that same thing like
whatever fake API is doing I'm trying to replicate that thing yeah okay now in
order to make like you know concurrent calls or parallel calls if you see I'm
making a promised at all and I'm trying to fetch all the user information and
use a post and then I'm trying to resolve it okay if I want to let's say
if I if I if you see it here in order to make this both things again like this is
an abstraction and there's another abstraction over that whenever you want
to pass a user ID and post ID how can you do this I just added this example
such that you can go through offline and you can explore this one and understand
okay then I've told you there's another example that I want to give you with
related to coffee let's say I say example 2.js let me copy that code which
I have it what have done in this example is like again still there is a producer
code like if you see whenever we go to cafe we call it get menu put an order
serve generate bill then payment and exit if you see I've still made a like
you know I've entered the cafe then I've added some conditions that what is the
time like let's say time is when your your cafe is open if it is above 6 and
less than 10 only then your cafe is open okay and then I have asked like
menu is shared or cafe is closed okay we can can you come back within six to
ten I've tried to build this example such that such a way that you can
understand is better then once you place an order let's say you have tea coffee
milkshake and biscuits in a menu and you say that can you give me an item one an
item two and that random item you will select out of it okay and once you
select that item order will be placed for you or else order will not be
available okay then you try to serve that particular order like you serve it
since serving takes time I have added five thousand milliseconds which is like
five seconds it will take five seconds to you know serve the order and I've
used only resolve there is no once order is placed I'm trying to fulfill it any
cost okay then billing they have made a static billing like 500 rupees okay is
this functions clear clear guys whatever functions that have declared here
pretty simple straightforward where I'm adding simple if else conditions I'm
also generating the promises for each function okay now since as I've told you
earlier that this actually shop example is something which happens in sequence
one after the other like there is no like parallel call being done here I have
added an example where you try to actually create a callback hell using
dot then this is called you can say promise hell not a callback hell where
you add dot then inside and placing an order right first you try to get the
menu once your menu you get the menu only then you try to place an order
right firstly I've said that I've entered into the shop at 7 p.m. and I
try to place an order of tea biscuit and then I'm asking them to serve it and
once they are serving it I'm trying to you know bill is getting generated and
then I'm trying to pay the bill and I'm thanking thanking for them service and
we go out of the restaurant this is a sequence steps is this large is this
clear guys the syntax how this thing works it's just straightforward but
the knowledge that we have you know consumed over the time the last three
classes right in order to make this better readable this looks like still
ugly in order to make this look for still better readable if you see what
async of it does now I made this code I say that cafe flow I made this function
like all there will be an async calls in that I built four options like you know
can you get me the menu at four at four it will be shop will be closed anyways
let me make a seven o'clock okay then I'm trying to place an order once I
place an order of tea and biscuits order will be served and then we will build
will be generated and once it is done then we'll make an payment if you see
in the generate bill itself okay we will be actually resolving the bill also we
are actually resolving it and there is no other functions that we have to wait
for then I'm trying to print the all the events is this clear how this is
happening in still in sequence order that using awaits I can execute this
example and show you to let's say I try to node example 2.js you see I entered
the cafe I have asked for the menu it says okay no once I have asked for the
menu if you see the menu is shared given order has been placed order is served
enjoy the time okay let's say if you see there is something which is taking long
amount of time once you have asked for the menu they're trying to get the menu
okay let's say yeah once you return the menu then you place an order okay for
serving an order it is taking five seconds that's where this is getting
so guys is this clear how do you make a sequence of events how do you handle
parallel events I've also shared an example where you actually handle the
parallel events this is the example let's say node example 1.js if I execute
this one if you see I press the user information and post information how did
I do it I say that fetch data user one and post one information and inside
this actually I made a promised at all trying to fetch all the user
information post-information to API calls in parallel and try to get that
data guys I was having a monologue for a long time just want to know if this
async await promises asynchronous code are you really comfortable with them is
those concepts clear in your head like we have seen event loop you have seen
execution like how JS get executed you know execution context memory creation
phase code execution phase all those topics yeah need to practice I
completely agree but I've so that I have made given so many good a great amount
of examples that you can go through and explore it anytime okay but what I need
from you guys is that you know try it build these examples when only when you
try to actually write down this one right let's see this like try to imagine
a scenario like when to use something like like a school event or a class
event or any event that you think when you want to go for parallel or when you
want to go for series when to use all when settled race all of them in if
you're in parallel then how do you handle using promises if I use promise
chaining like blood then blocks what is a challenge if I use async await how it
is cleaner code better code if you think this way and if you keep spend time on
it you will be able to get confidence over the time okay it will take time to
get that confidence and understanding when to use which one but I just want
you to be sure that the concepts that I am teaching or we are understanding here
that should be clear to you okay guys I hope this if there are anyone in anyone
who is having any challenge understanding this one right do let me
know I'll try to take it up okay
okay so there are a few things over I have to cover it let's say I say truth
the do you want me to cover it guys or you are already enough of it just want
to know you are if you want me to cover I can cover a few small things small J's
fundamentals okay everyone says no but really small example let's say if I have
like let's say a equal to undefined and if I write a console log to the value
and else console log false your value what do you think which would execute
what it should execute I mean just simple examples of JSC some it says
how many of you guys agree okay I see many of them are already tired I guess
understanding this concepts are going through this but pretty simple guys I
will try to okay let's let's execute this one you see it's a false like
whatever whenever value is undefined now if I convert this into 2l yes if I
convert this into 2l truth isn't it no so whenever there is something like value
is defined whenever value is defined or whenever there is a right sort of amount
of value or a data type let's say even if there is a string even if there is a
boolean value even if there is a number to assign to it that is actually
converted into boolean true one simple statement to well string let's say
random true okay this actually points to a true true thing I hope this point is
clear guys like whenever you have a actual value of any data type it will
be converted into true value then there are some use cases let's say like
undefined undefined conversion to falsi then what if I give it zero ways what if
I give it zero what do you think it should be should be true okay let's see
this it returns false zero or null all those things comes under falsi case
itself there is no value like zero actually should be actual value is like
not a whole number right which doesn't start from a zero is where this was a
bit of a trick question where I wanted to have that and also if you point to
null it still returns as false okay and we also know there's something called
NaN not a number when there's a data type which is not actually right data
type then it also returns us this one falsi condition and even empty string if
you give an empty string which doesn't have value real data value it returns
as falsi let's say if I give it a negative number let's say if I give a
negative number five minus five okay I try to execute it do you see that it's
a still true that's a real value I mean something from one to n numbers or mine
other than zero actually it converts into Boolean true whereas the other like
if you see our data types which are actually null in nature or doesn't have
any value undefined not a number empty strings you know all those things are
converted into falsi okay this is clear this is like a bit just a small things
that you should know that's why I wanted to talk off
yeah these are the errors that we see in assignments right generally zero you can
apply for it but zero doesn't have really any scope value now this also
doesn't really have any scope value right what if character without yeah
that's what I was talking right open draw let's say empty string okay it is
having and space but if I try to cover it up there is no space it returns
false if there is an empty space it will return me true so true t are those
conditions that does actually converts
into actual value is
let a equal to be expected or just a second expected as it would be something
like that so that our code give undefined yeah so let a equal to be I
didn't really get your point to pindra maybe if you can write it down further
I can talk about it
okay meanwhile open the type stone
me okay let him type but the this topic is clear right double equal to versus
triple equal to guys because we'll be using the all these topics concepts in
poly fields in next class for the classes I just want them to be in your mind
somewhere double equal to triple equal to we have covered already
right then do you remember what this operator is type of what this type of
does it's not a function but type of right just trying to know if you know
what if you want to if if it is a car instead of a number like
okay okay let's say let p equal to this one and be a equal to p is this example
up in the right here if I if you see this this is actually converting into
false condition let me try to show it okay it's still converting into truth
value okay okay here I didn't assign it actually sorry my mistake it should
convert into false itself I didn't save yet if you see this still if there is an
empty string which doesn't have any value it will convert into falsy only
when there is a value let's say if I give a space empty space here then it
will convert into true okay I hope that is making sense let's make some value
give it here save it so type of and double equal to is clear right okay now
there's a one more thing guys this is something you will see in the libraries
whenever you write JS libraries right let's say I have a const see an array of
one two three which have declared an array and if I want to let's say I say
that type of right type of C is triple equal to array only then we should go
ahead okay if this is a one type of syntax to know the data type of an array
then there is another way of checking it whether this is an array or not let's
say if I try to console dot log okay let's say this whatever is this is I
will try to print it other than this thing let's say console dot log array
array dot prototype inside that array dot prototype you have something like
ease array ease array always give returns your boolean value whether a
particular data type is an array or not both things are doing same thing let me
try to explore if you see this okay not triple equal to
since both are objects okay let me try to print this okay returning me an
object when I use type but if you want to compare arrays we have let's say is
our ease array method which is are coming from array dot prototype which is helping
us to compare okay whether it's an data type is an array or not whereas you can
use type of let's say if I go again type of its array is returning me an object
type of so I cannot really compare that but how can you check for the each
element is let's say if I go for arrow dot C of 0 let's see this if you see it
giving me a number if I have let's say a string it says saying random again I try
to do a console log of 1 and save it so I'm getting a string so a type of works
were in a good way when you go for primitive data types when you go for
actually objects and arrays they have built-in prototype methods like ease
array is a like the other available methods which will help us to know which
what type of data type it is is this point here guys like how to check the
type of an array
okay I'll end it here itself guys I don't want to stretch it further it's
there are few things that I have to cover but if if I try to push further it
will be really difficult for all right other things are pretty simple like how
do you play around with NA and checking the data type of NA and those
stuffs but there's any doubts and any doubts if you have any doubts guys
please stay in the call if there are no doubts feel free to drop try to complete
your assignments guys I'll be here for some time I'll be taking the doubts
there are a few doubts and added in the questions so I'll be addressing them if
you want me to revise anything I can take it up in next class also or also I
can do it now if you want in doubt session please hang in around if you
need anything any inputs from my side or if you don't have any doubts you can
feel free to drop and thank you for attending today's class and hope you see
on Thursday this week is primarily important guys since we'll be learning
polyfills which are mostly interview specific questions wherever you will be
tricked around like you will be mainly played around those questions we have
covered for call but we'll be recovering for the call bind apply and we'll also
see for this parallel calls promise dot all and all those things I'll share it
so that I'll put all those code bases across one places that's that you can go
through polyfills and machine coding it one shot okay guys so try to make sure
that you come to the class on the Thursday and you know understand those
thoughts whatever we learn together okay I'll try to give my best inputs there
again hope we hope you hope I see everyone again on the Thursday guys with
this I'm starting doubt session guys so I have started out session thanks some
with everything that's enough whole thing JS mock interview covers whole
thing LLD 1 LLD 2 both so to take it up Archana your question so in all settled
when the time limit exits we will not get an error so firstly there is nothing
like time limit exits firstly what I have done it here in this example let me
go to that example in all settle we I'm passing the time which is my manual
written code such that I'm expecting a time but what was my understanding that
this is the time taken to resolve an API call okay maybe there is some system
which is taking this amount of time to call so what all settled does is
irrespective of whatever time any call take only after all calls are successful
or failure when all calls are completed it might take 10 minutes 5 seconds 1
second 0 second milliseconds anything okay only when all calls are completed
and move to settled state only when they're moving to settle state if you
had like pending rejected fulfilled or settled right lasted once they receive
this API all calls are received to the settled state and only then this will go
into I mean then block okay this is clear when what all settled does it
actually consumes whether it's a I mean successful call or failure call doesn't
matter okay only only when it will go into a catch block is when all calls
fail okay when all of them are failing only then it will go or else your code
itself is wrong you have written some mistaken code when you when you're
making an API call okay so can I mark your question as answered you you guys
have to write around play around with this we've also shown you one of the
mock API where you can play around with the with that guys like you try it
around explore it in case you have any issues I'm here still anyways we can
still pick it up and go back and learn back okay I have marked your question as
answered Archana I'll pick Arun's question can we build a website like
after this course completion surely you should be able to build it maybe a
scaler clone you should be able to build it I'll check like if we can provide you
know a project I we may not teach it we will be teaching some other projects
because the each project is you know has an agenda through which we try to teach
many concepts but if there is a possibility if we can record and share
it with you we can do it but you will be having enough knowledge Arun so that you
will be able to build those projects whatever projects you want okay having
a capacity of understanding full front-end and good amount of Node.js
concepts will be enough we are enough equitable to build those okay because
we will be covering all those login authentication authorization concepts
everything few other topics which might I might not be able to cover in the part
of curriculum I'll be sharing the links URL which we can explore it I'll try to
pin in here okay and one thing I forgot is like I still didn't make you know
picture on something I have to I don't remember what I have to work on but I
forgot it yes anyone remember what I actually should have been working on one
picture which I left it this operator okay I remember so I'll can anyone
remind me in whatsapp chat I'll work tomorrow because I was not able to
recall it okay thank you so guys is there anything else any any other doubts
you have it I'll push the code let me
how all will differ in this example from all sector okay
no
promise start all again it takes our API calls like one two three four five okay
then we have something like dot then then we have dot catch right then you
have promise start sector you have again let's say two three four five six
seven okay this list of calls again you have then and catch when you go for
promised our dollar channel only when this is successful and fulfilled this is
successful and fulfilled this is also successful and fulfilled this is also
successful and fulfilled this is also successful and fulfilled only then it
will go into dot then if any of them is failing any of the call among them
series of calls fails everything will go into dot catch and all the things even
they are successful you won't be able to see the data because one API call got
failed it's just clear asana what promise what all does I've took one
example like this in a class you have 20 students even if one student makes noise
all of the other 19 also receive beatings this is the same example there's
a one problem with one API they all face issues whereas all certainly doesn't
really does that it returns to whatever data it has successful failure if you
again receive an array terms itself for this one this one all the things you can
go one by one and explore it guys can anyone share whatsapp chat let me try to
load it it will take time for me what's up what's up charting this group let me
load it I hope you all of you are also if you are able to manage time go
through that JavaScript art info I've mentioned good amount of time guys try
to go there explore that okay okay
this is the link Karthik Ganesh what should I call you Karthik it's Ganesh
or what's your name goes by okay Karthik so
so and guys and please try to complete your mock interviews also and you know
Abhinav is saying good name both name both name of both son and son of Shiva
okay huh Karthik and Ganesh both sons right so any other doubts guys Abhinav
have you started working on resume okay okay let me know once you start guys
anyone else who have their resume if they wanted any help let us let let us
know that we will try to add few suggestions and comments with all of us
so that our our end goal should be okay no worries Abhinav try to manage let's
see okay it's our end goal should be like going into a good workplace that we
have here we joined it for that reason so we try to make sure that don't take
anything personally just let's we are each other helping trying to help out
each other to grow better okay so with that guys if there are no further doubts
I'll end the session for today thank you all for attending today's class so hope
to see you all of you in the next class push this code base
this is class 26 oh we have completed more than 25 classes so guys I are you
enjoying understanding this concepts I'm trying to go as much as I can cover it
just wanted to know your feedback or or else we want you want us to improve on
something I've received feedback related to assignment problems that we can make
it more better examples rather than theory theoretical examples but if you
have anything do let us know it's good for us that we keep on improving you you
guys it's it's that we are giving back community giving back to the people
right so that we just want to know if you have any suggestions happy to take
okay
thank you Bidra good night good night guys take care then bye-bye
okay Pramod is saying two minutes sure Pramod do you want me to unmute you?
okay okay
is it normal that it is taking time to understand JS it is it is actually okay
firstly I would I would say right Pramod from any do when you're learning
anything for new for the first time it's it's always good that you try to revise
it if you remember the amount of time if you learn anything new right it takes
time to process it it takes time to get it but once you get the gist of it right
it would be really easy when you because everything needs a revision sort of
thing like if you want to revise because even for me right when I prep for the
class it takes some time so that I revise those concepts again I come and
teach it back because I have to build those examples and it's it's it's a
process it will happen for every time whenever you go for anything new it will
take time but in case you are not able to follow up or understand anything I'm
happy to help but just try to as you're saying that once you are attending again
you are able to understand it but when you understand it next time try to
revise the next day that's that would be my ask or advice you can say so that it
sticks in your mind it sticks there that thought or that topic whatever we have
learned so that you understand you remember it for the next time whenever it
come whenever you go back to that topic it is a just matter of minutes that you
revise them okay but it generally takes time but keep
revising that will be helpful because the concepts will be so much right end
of the day when you go for mock interview it will be overwhelming but
that's the reason why I keep saying that hey try to keep revising keep
revising because if you see from the last one month I haven't touched HTML
CSS all of sudden when we start react I'll again touch them so those topics
should be still refreshed like if I if we talk about grid if we talk about
flexbox right it takes some time but as soon as you see any documentation it
should be clear that you need not to again read each and every definition
right it should be the at that level of clear but I mean everything needs a
revision a number of times of revision but the amount of time it takes the
further and further when you revise it will be less and less okay okay great
wrong so can we end the session guys if there are no for any other further
questions from what we have anything else okay so you are solving your
assignment problems right from okay keep keep good to keep doing it try to build
those projects also in case you need any help let me know okay so the waste then
in the session good night guys take care bye bye
you